Preliminary Guide to the Carl Purington Rollins Papers
Yale University Arts Library
- Presses, 1902-1963; Series VI
  - Pudgy Bear Press, undated (Box 29)
  - Pudgy Bear Press, 1939 (Box 50)
  - Quercus Press, 1937 (Box 29)
  - Rampant Lions Press, 1941 (Box 30)
  - Random House, 1928 (Box 30)
  - Random House, 1930 (Box 48)
  - Red Tower Press, 1940-1943 (Box 30)
  - Redcoat Press, 1940-1943 (Box 30)
  - Reed Pale Press, 1935 (Box 30)
  - Riccardi Press, 1913 (Box 30)
  - Richard Clay and Sons, 1925-1926 (Box 30)
  - Rudge, William, 1926-1932 (Box 30)
  - Rutgers University Press, undated (Box 30)
  - Rydal Press, 1936-1938 (Box 30)
  - Saint Dominic's Press, 1934 (Box 30)
  - San Pasqual Press, 1939 (Box 30)
  - Salt House Press, 1928-1930 (Box 30)
  - Scholartis Press, 1929-1930 (Box 30)
  - Shakespeare Head Press, 1923-1932 (Box 30)
  - Shenval Press, The, 1958 (Box 30)
  - Shoe String Press, The, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Short Run Press, undated (Box 30)
  - Sign of the Dolphin, 1931 (Box 30)
  - Slide Mountain Press, 1930 (Box 30)
  - Soncino Press, 1930-1931 (Box 30)
  - Southworth-Anthoensen Press, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
  - Spiral Press, 1930-1935 (Box 30)
  - Spread Eagle Press, 1942 (Box 30)
  - Stanford Press, 1950 (Box 30)
  - Steller-Millar, 1936 (Box 30)
  - Stinehour Press, 1957 (Box 30)
  - Stone Wall Press, 1960 (Box 30)
  - Sun (NYC), The, 1933 (Box 47)
  - Sunnyside Press, 1933 (Box 30)
  - Syracuse University Press, 1948 (Box 48)
  - Taylor & Taylor, 1920-1938 (Box 31)
  - Times (London), The, 1929,1932,1935 (Box 47)
  - Trovillion Private Press, 1938-1958 (Box 31)
  - Thomsen-Ellis Co., undated (Box 31)
  - Typographer, 1954 (Box 31)
  - Typography Society, undated (Box 31)
  - University of California Press, 1953 (Box 31)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1941-1948 (Box 31)
  - University Press (Cambridge), 1925 (Box 31)
  - University of Hawaii Press, 1949 (Box 31)
  - University of Oregon Press, 1939 (Box 31)
  - Underfoot Press, 1952-1959 (Box 31)
  - Village Press, 1938 (Box 48)
  - Ward Ritchie Press (Box 32)
  - Ward Ritchie Press, 1937-1941 (Box 48)
  - Wayside Press, undated (Box 32)
  - White Knight Press, 1949-1952 (Box 32)
  - William Byrd Press, 1957 (Box 32)
  - Williamsburg Press, 1935-1948 (Box 32)
  - Williamsburg Press, 1935-1948 (Box 32)
  - Windsor Press, undated (Box 32)
  - Windsor Press, 1927 (Box 48)
  - Wood, Clarke Press, 1923 (Box 32)
  - University of Chicago Press, undated (Box 32)
  - Yale University Library, 1954 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Presses (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous Presses (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous Presses (Box 55)
- Printers and Designers, 1897-1976; Series VII
  This series contains ephemeral publications, prospecti, broadsides, etc., designed or issued by various designers and printers.
  - Abbott Laboratories, undated (Box 47)
  - Amigos de Calle del Cristo, undated (Box 34)
  - Armitage, Merle, undated (Box 34)
  - Beck Engraving Co., 1931 (Box 34)
  - Bennett, Paul A., undated (Box 34)
  - Bentley, Wilder, undated (Box 34)
  - Bernhardt, Mark, 1976 (Box 51)
  - Boosten and Stols, undated (Box 34)
  - Bradford, W. (Box 34)
  - Bradley, Will, 1897-1954, undated (Box 34)
  - Bradley, Will, undated (Box 49)
  - Bucholz, R. J., 1930 (Box 34)
  - Bumpus, John & Edward, undated (Box 34)
  - Capon, Charles R., 1924-1925 (Box 34)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1959 (Box 34)
  - Carr, Horace, 1910-1941 (Box 34)
  - Cleland, T. M., undated (Box 34)
  - Cleland, T. M., undated (Box 49)
  - Colish, A., undated (Box 59)
  - DeRenne, Kentwyn, 1935-1936 (Box 34)
  - Diderot, undated (Box 51)
  - Dwiggins, W. A. (about him), 1957 (Box 34)
  - Dwiggins Designs (Box 34)
  - Dwiggins, W. A., undated (Box 34–35)
  - Dwiggins, W. A. (Society of Calligraphers), undated (Box 35)
  - Dwiggins, W. A., undated (Box 35)
  - Dwiggins, W. A. (Box 49)
  - Dwiggins, W. A. (Yale University Press), undated (Box 49)
  - Dwiggins, W. A., 1924 (Box 51)
  - Dwiggins, W. A. (originals for Yale University Press) (Box 51)
  - Etchells and MacDonald (Box 35)
  - Farquar, Samuel, 1935 (Box 35)
  - Geist, Ellsworth, undated (Box 35)
  - Goldston, Edward, undated (Box 35)
  - Goodhue, Bertram, 1924 (Box 35)
  - Goudy, Frederic (about), undated (Box 36)
  - Goudy, Frederic (designed by), undated (Box 36)
  - Goudy, Frederic (designed by), undated (Box 36)
  - Goudy, Frederic (written by), undated (Box 37)
  - Goudy, Frederic (35th Anniversary of Village Press), undated (Box 37)
  - Goudy, Frederic (Typographica), undated (Box 37)
  - Goudy, Frederic (misc.), undated (Box 37)
  - Grafton and Co., undated (Box 38)
  - Hall, Frederic, undated (Box 38)
  - Halycon-Commonwealth Foundation, 1964 (Box 38)
  - Hammer, Victor, undated (Box 38)
  - Hammer, Victor, 1931 (Box 51)
  - Heppenheimer and Maurer (Box 38)
  - Hoover, Roland A. (Box 51)
  - Hopgard, Theodore R., 1923-1924 (Box 38)
  - Hunter, Dard, undated (Box 49)
  - Huse, William H., undated (Box 38)
  - Inman, Maurice, undated (Box 51)
  - Joh. Enschede en Zonen, undated (Box 38)
  - Kent, Rockwell, undated (Box 38)
  - Kitson, Harry G., undated (Box 38)
  - Knopf, A. A., 1959 (Box 38)
  - Kochler, Henry, undated (Box 57)
  - Kredel, Fritz, undated (Box 38)
  - Laughlin, Curtis Stuart, 1928 (Box 38)
  - Le Gallienne, Richard, undated (Box 38)
  - Lindacker, Max, 1956 (Box 51)
  - Mackenzie and Harris, undated (Box 49)
  - Main, F. W., 1924 (Box 38)
  - Marchbanks, Hal, 1915 (Box 49)
  - McCrillis, John, undated (Box 38)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas, 1932 (Box 51)
  - Morris, William, undated (Box 38)
  - Nash, John, 1926-1932 (Box 51)
  - Nash, 1937-1948 (Box 38)
  - Nash, undated (Box 38)
  - Nash, undated (Box 49)
  - Nash, undated (Box 55)
  - Nypels, Charles, 1953 (Box 47)
  - Payne, Roger, 1937 (Box 38)
  - Penniman, John R., undated (Box 38)
  - Pepler, Douglas, 1918 (Box 38)
  - Phelps, Fred Totton, 1951 (Box 38)
  - Pichon, Leon, 1932 (Box 38)
  - Pynson Printers, 1922-1941 (Box 39)
  - Pynson Printers, 1929 (Box 49)
  - Ransom, Will, 1922-1946 (Box 39)
  - Ritchie, Harry, undated (Box 39)
  - Robbins Publications, undated (Box 39)
  - Rogers, Bruce, undated (Box 39)
  - Rogers, Bruce, undated (Box 40)
  - Rogers, Bruce, 1902-1904 (Box 51)
  - Rosa and Rosa, undated (Box 40)
  - Rosa and Rosa, undated (Box 49)
  - Rudge, William, 1926 (Box 51)
  - Rueckert, undated (Box 40)
  - Rullman, Fred, undated (Box 40)
  - Schering-Kahlbaum, undated (Box 41)
  - Schoonmaker, undated (Box 41)
  - Sherbow, Benjamin, 1913 (Box 41)
  - Sills, Charlotte & Malcolm, 1937 (Box 41)
  - Taylor, Edward, undated (Box 41)
  - Taylor and Taylor, 1915-1918 (Box 41)
  - Taylor and Taylor (Box 49)
  - Thomas Todd Co., 1909 (Box 41)
  - Topolski, Feliks, 1953 (Box 41)
  - Townshend, Henry, 1934 (Box 41)
  - Trenholm, George, undated (Box 41)
  - Typographic Craftsman, undated (Box 49)
  - Updike, D.B., undated (Box 41)
  - Updike, D.B., 1901-1947 (Box 41)
  - Walpole Printing Office, 1931 (Box 41)
  - Walpole Printing Office, undated (Box 49)
  - Warde, Frederic, 1926 (Box 41)
  - Wetmore, Edith, undated (Box 41)
  - Wheelwright, William, 1929 (Box 41)
  - William Morris Society, undated (Box 41)
  - Williams, Thomas, undated (Box 41)
  - Witherspoon, A. M., 1938-1942 (Box 41)
  - Woolsey, John, 1938 (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous Printers and Designers, Portraits (Box 55)
  - Unidentified broadsides and images (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous facsimiles and broadsides (Box 57)
- Paper Specimens, 1877-1942; Series VIII
  - American Writing Paper Co., undated (Box 42)
  - Asia Printing Specimen, undated (Box 47)
  - Bedmann, Johan, undated (Box 42)
  - Bibliographic Society, The, 1935 (Box 42)
  - Byron Weston Co., 1929 (Box 42)
  - Champion Coated Paper Company, The, 1922 (Box 42)
  - Chemical Foundation, The, 1934 (Box 42)
  - Don Wing, undated (Box 42)
  - Eastwood Wire Corp., 1877 (Box 42)
  - Giulio Giannini & Son Publishers, undated (Box 42)
  - Japan Paper Company, undated (Box 42)
  - Journalism Laboratory Press, 1939 (Box 42)
  - Samuel Kirk and Son, undated (Box 42)
  - Laurentide Pulp Co., The, 1902 (Box 42)
  - P. D. Perkins, 1940 (Box 42)
  - Printing Art, The, undated (Box 42)
  - Herbert Reichner Derlag, 1933 (Box 42)
  - Rohm and Haam Co., undated (Box 42)
  - Sale, William M., undated (Box 42)
  - 1750 Paper, undated (Box 42)
  - Stevens-Nelson Corporation, undated (Box 42)
  - Storm, Nancy M., undated (Box 42)
  - Von Asten and Co., 1936 (Box 42)
  - S. D. Warren Co., 1942 (Box 42)
  - Wheelwright, W.B., 1938-39 (Box 42)
  - Whiting Plover Paper Co., undated (Box 42)
  - Whitney Anderson Paper Company, undated (Box 42)
  - Unidentified volume, undated (Box 42)
  - Whitaker Paper Co., undated (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous paper specimens, undated (Box 49)
- Type Specimens, 1929-1949; Series IX
  - Aldus Type, 1929 (Box 43)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1947 (Box 43)
  - American Type Founders Co., 1929-1930 (Box 43)
  - Augustin, J. J., undated (Box 43)
  - Bauer Type Foundry, 1941 (Box 43)
  - Binny and Ronaldson Foundry, undated (Box 51)
  - Bullard, H. O., undated (Box 43)
  - W. H. Caslon and Co., undated (Box 49)
  - Continental Typefounders, undated (Box 49)
  - Copper and Brass Bulletin, 1947 (Box 43)
  - Crittenden, Walter, undated (Box 43)
  - Diamant Typographic, undated (Box 43)
  - Eastern Caslon, undated (Box 51)
  - Haddon Craftsmen, undated (Box 43)
  - E. L. Hildreth & Co., undated (Box 43)
  - Mergenthaler Linotype Company, 1949 (Box 43)
  - Monotype Corporation, undated (Box 43)
  - Monotypesetting Co., 1940 (Box 43)
  - Munsell Color Systems, undated (Box 43)
  - Nebiolo Company, undated (Box 43)
  - Chas D. O'Brien, Inc., undated (Box 43)
  - Rumford Press, undated (Box 43)
  - Southwork Press, undated (Box 43)
  - Southern New England Typographic Service, undated (Box 43)
  - Stephenson Blake, undated (Box 43)
  - Theosophical University Press, undated (Box 43)
  - Cecil H. Wrightson, Inc., undated (Box 43)
  - Yale's Oriental Type, undated (Box 43)
  - Rollins's list of types, undated (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous type specimens, undated (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous type specimens, undated (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous type specimens, undated (Box Bsd)
  - Miscellaneous type specimens in volume, undated (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous type specimens in volume, undated (Box 58)
    As per note by CPR, some of these type specimens are rare. (Oversize +)
- Library and Museum Publications, 1910-1962; Series X (Box 58)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, The, 1940,1960 (Box 44)
  - American Library, The, 1954 (Box 44)
  - Amherst, undated (Box 44)
  - Annapolitan Library at St. John's College, undated (Box 44)
  - Bibliographical Society of America, 1954 (Box 44)
  - Boston Public Library, undated (Box 44)
  - Brattleboro Free Library, 1937 (Box 44)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, undated (Box 49)
  - Chapin Library, undated (Box 44)
  - Clements Library, undated (Box 44)
  - Clements Library, undated (Box 49)
  - Colonial Williamsburg, 1950 (Box 44)
  - Columbia University Library, undated (Box 44)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1934 (Box 44)
  - Houghton Library, 1952 (Box 44)
  - Huntington Library, undated (Box 44)
  - Gemeentemuseum, 1950 (Box 45)
  - Industrial Graphic Arts Library, The, 1933 (Box 47)
  - John Carter Brown Library, 1962 (Box 45)
  - Sarah Cecilia Krakowski Memorial Library, The, 1950 (Box 45)
  - Library of Congress, undated (Box 45)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, The, 1952 (Box 45)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1910 (Box 51)
  - National Library of Peiping, 1934 (Box 45)
  - Newberry Library, 1955 (Box 45)
  - Peabody Institute, The, 1953-1954 (Box 45)
  - Peabody Museum, undated (Box 45)
  - Piermont Morgan Library, 1957 (Box 45)
  - Pratt Institute Library, 1935 (Box 45)
  - Princeton University Library, 1949-1954 (Box 45)
  - RISD Museum of Art, 1945 (Box 45)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology, undated (Box 45)
  - Rutgers University, undated (Box 45)
  - Scripps College, 1962 (Box 45)
  - Trinity College Library, undated (Box 49)
  - Typographic Library and Museum, undated (Box 49)
  - University of Chicago, 1935 (Box 45)
  - Yale University Art Gallery, 1950-1953 (Box 45)
  - Yale University School of Medicine, 1960 (Box 45)
- Photographs and Realia, 1902-1958; Series XI
  - Photographs
    - Photographs of CPR (Box 46)
    - Photographs of CPR with others (Box 46)
    - Photographs of Dyke Mill and an unidentified printing press (Box 46)
    - Photographic portrait of unidentified man (Box 46)
    - Photograph of Rollins at a press, 1903 (Box 57)
    - Photograph of a woman (Mrs. Margaret Rollins?) in front of home (Box 57)
  - Realia
    - Receipts, bills and invoices, and an invitation to Elizabeth Rollins wedding, 1932-1958, undated (Box 46)
    - Address book containing addresses and other information relating to a European trip (Box 46)
    - Austrian currency: 1000 Kronen bill (Box 46)
    - Envelope for buttons from Galeries Lafayette, Paris (Box 46)
    - Menu from an Amherst Club Luncheon (Box 46)
    - Name card from Yale University (Box 46)
    - B & R Dinner souvenir, 1935 (Box 46)
    - Paper mould (Box Drw 17)
    - Tools to cut punches (from Warren Kilburn) (Box Drw 17)
- Notebooks, 1903-1958; Series XII
  Rollins maintained notebooks containing correspondence, research materials, type specimens, photographs, and a wide variety of other documents. He filed much of this material in ring binders according to a numerical classification scheme he devised. There is no key to the classification system. The box listing below provides the classification number ("Spine Title") appearing on the spine of each notebook, followed by a brief description of the "Contents" of each numbered classification or sub-classification of material contained in the notebook as designated by tabbed dividers. Bracketed ( [ ] ) content descriptions were supplied by the processing archivist. A listing of material in notebooks to which Rollins did not assign a classification number follows the classified material. This "unclassified" notebook material has been removed from binders and placed in folders, but original order has been maintained. Index cards which formed a catalogue of the notebooks are in two alphabetical sequences.
  - Classified Notebooks
    - 1.124 [Letter about editions of Shakespeare] (Box 59)
    - 2.3 Forgeries (Box 59)
    - 3.21 [AAUP] (Box 59)
    - 3.3 [Various book people] (Box 59)
    - 4.0 Book selling (Box 59)
    - 5.0 (Box 59)
    - 6.0 [Librarians] (Box 59)
    - 7.0 [Libraries] (Box 59)
    - 8.0 (Box 59)
    - 9.0 (Box 59)
    - Thomas Bird Mosher (Box 59)
    - 10.2 [Description of Bozeng's History of the Art of Book Printing, 1928] (Box 59)
    - 12.4 Almanacs/Calendars (Box 59)
    - 12.5 Hornbooks, educational (Box 59)
    - 13.0 Newspapers (Box 59)
    - 13.6 Saturday Review of Literature letter (Box 59)
    - 14.0 Rare and curious (Box 59)
    - 15.0 Famous books (Box 59)
    - 16.0 [Letters from people responding to Rollins's request for a list of ten most influential books in various fields.] (Box 59)
    - 16.0 Bible (Box 59)
    - 17.3 Book collectors (Box 59)
    - 18.0 Book clubs (Box 59)
    - 20.0 [Handwriting] (Box 59)
    - 22.1 [Sign language chart] (Box 59)
    - 22.2 [Letter regarding two characters not used in Modern English] (Box 59)
    - 22.3 Monograms [envelope containing a collection of monograms given to CPR] (Box 59)
    - 23.0 [Manuscript illumination] (Box 59)
    - 24.0-26.0 [Manuscripts] (Box 59)
    - Writing (Box 59)
    - Short List of Books About Printing (Box 59)
    - The Printing Art (Box 59)
    - [Humorous articles, cartoons, etc.], 3; notebooks (Box 59)
    - Poems (Box 59)
    - 30.0 [Article on printing] (Box 59)
    - 30.1 Bibliography of printing (Box 59)
    - 30.3 Dictionary (Box 59)
    - 31.1 Gutenberg Incunabula (Box 59)
    - 32.11 (Box 59)
    - 32.12 (Box 59)
    - 32.13 History [of Printing] U.S. by state (Box 59)
    - 32.14 [History of Printing] U.S. by cities (Box 59)
    - 32.15 [History of Printing] Mexico & Spanish America (Box 59)
    - 32.16 Early Peruvian Printing Office (Box 59)
    - 32.3 Early Printing in France (Box 59)
    - 32.42 [Early Printing in] Germany, by cities (Box 59)
    - 32.52 [Early Printing in] Italy, by cities (Box 59)
    - 32.97 [Early Printing in] Asia (Box 59)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 60)
    - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 61)
      See also Box 8 for Bruce Rogers.
    - Spine Title 33.1 T[-W] (Box 61)
      - [Biographical information on printers alphabetized by last name] (Box 61)
    - Oporinus [, Johannes] (Box 61)
    - Famous Presses (Box 61)
    - Museum Plantin Moretus (Box 61)
    - Typography, 15th-19th century, commentary, examples, etc. (Box 61)
    - 14th-15th c. manuscript and type (Box 61)
    - 15th c. typography (Box 61)
    - 16th c. typography, 2; notebooks (Box 61)
    - 17th c. typography, 2; notebooks (Box 61)
    - 18th c. Bastard titles and Title pages (Box 62)
    - 18th c. Dedicatory Epistles and Text pages (Box 62)
    - 18th c. Title pages (Box 62)
    - 18th c. Typography (Box 62)
    - 19th c., 3 notebooks (Box 62)
    - 20th c. typography (Box 62)
    - 35.02 Civil Services exam announcement for printing trade (Box 63)
    - 35.03 Printer's manuals (Box 63)
    - 35.2 Machinery (Box 63)
    - 35.21 [Type] Styles, History, Names (Box 63)
    - 35.22 Type Foundries (Box 63)
    - 35.23 Machinery for Manufacturing Type (Box 63)
    - 35.24 Prices (Box 63)
    - Paper (Box 63)
    - 35.4.1 Materials (Box 63)
    - 35.4.2 Machinery (Box 63)
    - 35.4.3 Samples (Box 63)
    - 35.4.4 Sizes, weights, qualities (Box 63)
    - 35.4.5 Watermarks (Box 63)
    - 35.4.6 History of Manufacture (Box 63)
    - 35.4.7 History of Paper Dealers (Box 63)
    - 35.4.8 Biographies of Paper Makers (Box 63)
    - 35.5.1 Exhibitions and Museums (Box 63)
    - De Vinne, Theodore Low [typed manuscript; articles; notes; letters regarding DeVinne] (Box 63)
    - 35.51 Composition (Box 63)
    - 35.55 Composing Machines (Box 63)
    - 35.7 Proof-reading (Box 63)
    - Presses (Box 63)
    - 36.8 Color Work (Box 63)
    - 37.0 Other Processes Used in Printing (Box 63)
    - Stereotyping (Box 63)
    - 39.6 Labor Unions (Box 63)
    - 43.5 Bibliography of English and Illustrations (Box 63)
    - 46.0 Processes in Illustration (Box 63)
    - 48.0 Card Printing (Box 63)
    - 48.7 Postal Art [includes examples of postage stamps] (Box 63)
    - 48.9 Maps (Box 63)
    - 50.0 [Bookbinding] (Box 63)
    - 51.4 "Bookbinding in England" (Box 63)
    - 92.0 Individual Biography (Box 63)
    - 96.0 Portraits (Box 63)
    - [Zeese-Wilkinson Co.] (Box 63)
    - German Vignettes 1750 (Box 63)
    - [Notebook containing article on William Alexander Jackson and 1965 February issue of Yale University Library Staff News] (Box 63)
    - [Examples of printing (bookplates) by Bruce Rogers, Henry Koehler, Robin Galvin, etc.] (Box 64)
    - Bookplates designed by CPR, 4; notebooks (Box 64)
  - Unclassified Notebooks
    - Agathynian Club, 1947-1949 (Box 65)
    - Dyke Mill: letters, photos, and clippings, 1907-1944; 2 (Box 65)
    - Rogers, Bruce: portraits (Box 65)
    - Rollins's letters, clippings, etc.
      - "of [19]20s", 3 (Box 65)
      - "of [19]30s", 3 (Box 65)
      - "of [19]40s", 4 (Box 65)
      - "of [19]50s", 2 (Box 65)
    - Rollins's correspondence, clippings, etc., relating to Yale University Press books arranged alphabetically by book title
      - A-I (Box 65)
      - J-Y (Box 65)
    - Rollins's retirement: letters, clippings, 1948 (Box 65)
    - Rollins's designs and proofs, 1903-1948 (Box 65)
    - Rollins's writings and related correspondence, 3 (Box 65)
    - [19th c. typography] examples, 2 (Box 65)
    - Type specimens
      - A-L (Box 65)
      - M-P (Box 65)
      - R-S (Box 65)
      - T-W, and catalogue of selections (Box 65)
    - "Scrapbooks of typefaces…" (Box 66)
      Transferred from Manuscripts and Archives, July 2005; formerly Yns71 +2.
    - "Initials, printers' marks, etc., collected by Carl Rollins…", 2 (Box 66)
      Transferred from Manuscripts and Archives, July 2005; formerly Yns71 +3.
    - Yale University Press Ornaments (Box 66)
    - Merrymount Press printed ephemera (Box 66)
    - Bruce Rogers (33.1.R) volume containing correspondence, printed items, etc. (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous loose notebook material (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous loose notebook material (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous title pages (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 67)
    - Stevens-Nelson Paper Corp. paper samples, 2 (Box 67)
    - Index card catalogue to Rollins's notebooks (Box 68)
- 2002 Addition, 1903-1974
  - Correspondence of CPR
    - A-D, 1920-1961 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Frederick, 1950-1959 (Box 1)
    - Aiken, Judge John A., 1918-1923 (Box 1)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1925-1959 (Box 1)
    - Bennett, Paul, 1934-1957 (Box 1)
    - Dreyfus, John G., 1957-1964 (Box 1)
    - E-K, 1919-1959 (Box 1)
    - Hofer, Philip, 1931-1957 (Box 1)
    - L-R, 1920-1958 (Box 1)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1931-1970 (Box 1)
    - Page, Charles, 1923, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Phinney, J. W., 1914-1935 (Box 1)
    - S-T, 1918-1960 (Box 1)
    - Seymour, George D., 1920-1941 (Box 1)
    - V-Z, 1918-1957 (Box 1)
    - Wilder Family, 1948-1958 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1924-1962 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified correspondents (first name only, A-Z), 1927-1958 (Box 1)
    - Third-party correspondence (A-W), 1925-1961 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence of Margaret Rollins (Mrs. Carl P. Rollins)
    - A-K, 1937-1972 (Box 1)
    - Heckscher, August, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
    - Hugo, Harold, 1962-1974 (Box 1)
    - Kerr, Chester, 1960-1972 (Box 1)
    - L-Z, 1939-1969 (Box 1)
    - Leekley, Richard, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - Sizer, Theodore, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    - Weyerhaeuser, Carl, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
    - Wilder Family, 1938-1968 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified correspondents (first name only, A-Z), 1938-1965 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Booklets plan, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Galley for "A Selected List of Books Set on the Linotype and Printed for the Yale University Press," p. 1-16, 1922 (Box 1)
    - Preliminary Synopsis for a "History of Printing", 1940 (Box 1)
    - [History of Printing], chapters 1, 2, 8, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 13, 14, 15 and Notes (Box 1)
    - "Momentous Changes in the Nineteenth Century" and "Changes in the Nineteenth Century" (Box 1)
    - "On Being a Rural Socialist", circa 1912 (Box 1)
    - Speech for the opening of "Printing for Commerce" exhibit at the Art Center, New York City, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Notes for Rollins's undergraduate course in bibliography (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous writings by CPR and others, 1926-1949 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, etc., on Thornton Wilder, 1962-1969 (Box 1)
  - Personal papers
    - Papers including birth certificates of CPR and Caroline Rollins, 1880-1960 (Box 1)
  - Materials relating to New Clairvaux, Dyke Mill, and Montague Press
    - Diary/Guest book from Dyke Mill, 1920-1939 (Box 2)